<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rds on Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/tags/rds/</link><description>Recent content in Rds on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/tags/rds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why is RDS not just an Open-Source PostgreSQL? From Classic RDS to Aurora DSQL</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-amazon-aurora-dsql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-amazon-aurora-dsql/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aws-user-group-singapore">
 AWS User Group Singapore
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#aws-user-group-singapore">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was invited to the AWS User Group Singapore to talk about the PostgreSQL in AWS and about the Amazon Aurora DSQL. It was a great event. I was happy to meet many engineers and architects from the community. Usuage of the PostgreSQL in Singapore is quite huge, around half of audince was using it.
Organization of the event was perfect. I was happy to be a part of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MVP on AWS: PostgreSQL</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-mvp-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-mvp-postgresql/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-postgresql">
 Why PostgreSQL?
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#why-postgresql">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you already decided on PostgreSQL as your database. Why? Because it is a powerful, open-source object-relational database system with over 30 years of active development, correct? We will leave the problem of where and how to store data for another time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="rds-aurora-postgresql-compatible-or-rds-postgresql">
 RDS Aurora (PostgreSQL Compatible) or RDS PostgreSQL
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#rds-aurora-postgresql-compatible-or-rds-postgresql">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If there are no specific requirements, we may select Aurora as the default option.
Storage systems are the key difference between the two. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about being out of space. Aurora will help you. Aurora will automatically scale the storage up to 128 TB (November 2024). &amp;ldquo;The data is automatically replicated across Availability Zones, your data is highly durable with less possibility of data loss.&amp;rdquo; You can have one instance with data in 3 different places. If you want to add another region, it will give us six different places in the world where data is stored. Magic, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS RDS Data API and CloudTrail. Who drop the table?</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-rds-data-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-rds-data-api/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">
 Introduction
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#introduction">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Amazon Web Services (AWS) continually innovates to enhance user experience and efficiency. A prime example of this is the recent update to the RDS Data API, particularly for Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible Edition. This update is a game-changer, as it offers users the ability to access Aurora clusters via a secure HTTP endpoint. The key here is the removal of rate limits and the elimination of the need for database drivers and managing connections.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>