<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</guid><description>Developers often hardcode credentials on a public or private GitHub repository, ramping up data leakage risks. It’s hardly better to store static credentials in the .aws/credentials folder on a server or a local operator machine. As american cryptographer, writer, and computer security specialist, Bruce Schneier, says: . &amp;ldquo;Only amateurs attackWe machines; professionals target people.&amp;rdquo; Therefore, you, not your hardware, is at risk.
By executing fraudulent software, cybercriminals can easily steal all the data from the folder or a whole directory with your, your friends’, and clients’ credentials.</description></item><item><title>What Is AWS CloudTrail, and Why Do You Need It</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</guid><description>Don’t have enough resources to set up a security department but want to stay on top of your AWS CloudTrail events? Find out how the CloudTrail-to-Slack Terraform module by FivexL solves this problem for startups and small teams.
Terraform Module for AWS CloudTrail — An Effective Security Tool Link to heading While large corporations have their own Security Operations Centers (SOCs) responsible for information security and can afford expensive solutions, startups usually don’t have enough resources and time to set up such a luxury.</description></item><item><title>How To Save Resources With the Terraform Module for AWS Spot Instances</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</guid><description>Saving money on Amazon Web Services (AWS) Spot Instances can be a challenging task. Keep in mind that it is essentially an auction. Although prices don’t fluctuate as rapidly as on exchanges, they can still increase until they reach the on-demand rate. Sometimes it lasts for a day or two, but other times — up to several months, which can double the cost.
How do you avoid a situation in which, for example, everything went perfect in November, but in December, the prices doubled amid the holiday hype — and you got not only an expensive system but also one with interruptions?</description></item><item><title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/migrate-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/migrate-to-hugo/</guid><description>I was happy to switch to Hugo I think this format looks much more modern</description></item><item><title>Cageyv GitHub</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/cageyv-github/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/cageyv-github/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/about/</guid><description>Personality Link to heading Organized and responsible
Self-directive, I only need to know a direction - will figure out a way on my own
Quick-learner, eager to learn and share with the team
Easy going, open and non-conflicting
Team-player, using my experience to upskill and support the team
Bio Link to heading Cloud Engineering Specialist
Independent consultant
10+ experience in ops, infra automation, development
Certified AWS architect
HashiCorp tools specialist</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/contact/</guid><description>Follow me, @cageyv.</description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/education/</guid><description>2010 - 2014: Moscow State University of Instrument Engineering and Computer Science Master Degree, GPA: 4.55 / 5 Computers, complexes, systems, and networks 2006 - 2010: Moscow College of Informatics and Computer Engineering Engineer’s degree, GPA: 4.23 / 5 Computer software and automated systems Additional Education Link to heading AWS Link to heading https://www.aws.training/
2021 aws certified solutions architect associate
2020 aws technical professional
2020 aws cloud economics
2020 aws business professional</description></item><item><title>Experience</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/experience/</guid><description>2020 - present: FivexL consulting team Skills: Amazon ECS · AWS Lambda · AWS Security · GitHub · Amazon Web Services (AWS) · Terraform Various projects Clients meet where they are and no matter how chaotic and confusing were, everything was managed to be put on the rails of predictability All wishes and requirements for the project were carefully listened to. Deep understanding of client requirements, needs, and challenges Skeletons in the closet are not a problem.</description></item><item><title>First snippet</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/first/</guid><description>This content is in snippets/first/index.md
pwd</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/projects/</guid><description>Secure, durable and scalable Infrastrature for Europenian Crypto Exchange Platform Link to heading “It was an essential approach for us to be able to scale moving forward.” and &amp;ldquo;first application deployed in just two weeks.” (c)
Migration from AWS EC2 to AWS ECS (Containers) like a hot swap wheel change on a moving race car Pipeline migration from Buddyworks to GitHub Actions Serverless solution (AWS ECS Fargate + AWS Lambda) Security part: Database are not available for all world any more, CMK KMS as general for encryption, AWS WAF + Cloudflare for incoming traffic protection Resource Optimization: Resource usage has been reduced by more than 50% and we will improve the ecology of the world.</description></item><item><title>Recommend</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/recommend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/recommend/</guid><description>Servies Link to heading Numbeo Do you want to compare Cities or Countries? Cost of living and Quality of Life database is here. DuoLingo The free, fun, and effective way to learn a language! Onward Ticket Quickly book a Flight Reservation for your Visa Application. Verifiable on Airline&amp;rsquo;s Websites. SafetyWing Insurance for nomdas. Travel medical insurance. They cover people from all over the world, while outside their home country. Audible Audiobooks, Originals, and podcasts Feedly Track insights across the web without having to read everything.</description></item><item><title>Second snippet</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/second/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/second/</guid><description>This content is in snippets/second/index.md
ls -la</description></item></channel></rss>