<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/</link><description>Recent content on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book: Pitch Anything: An Innovative Method for Presenting, Persuading, and Winning the Deal, Oren Klaff (2011)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/pitch-anything/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/pitch-anything/</guid><description>https://www.amazon.com/Pitch-Anything-Innovative-Presenting-Persuading/dp/0071752854
Introduction Link to heading Have you ever realized that every interaction is a pitch? Be it job interviews, dating, or meeting new people, we&amp;rsquo;re constantly &amp;lsquo;selling&amp;rsquo; ourselves. This realization hit me hard after diving into Oren Klaff&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Pitch Anything,&amp;rdquo; a book that reshapes the art of persuasion. My journey in the IT consulting world has been profoundly impacted by this book, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share these insights with you.</description></item><item><title>Navigating the Path to AWS Solutions Architect Professional Certification</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-solutions-architect-professional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-solutions-architect-professional/</guid><description>Embarking on a Transformative Journey Link to heading Two years ago, I set out on an educational expedition with AWS, starting with the AWS Solutions Architect Associate certification. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m elated to share my achievement of the AWS Solutions Architect Professional certification. This accomplishment marks a significant milestone in my professional journey.
Empowered by the AWS Community Builders Program Link to heading My path was significantly bolstered by the support of the AWS Community Builders program.</description></item><item><title>scb-to-moneywiz: Import Bank Transactions from SCB Easy (Thailand) to MoneyWiz</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/scb-to-moneywiz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/scb-to-moneywiz/</guid><description>Introduction: Link to heading Navigating financial management can be a tricky affair, especially without cutting-edge banking technology. But for users of MoneyWiz, an ingenious script is making life easier. This tool specifically aids in importing SCB Bank transactions, transforming a tedious task into a smooth, automated process.
The Challenge with SCB Bank: Link to heading As we approach the end of 2023, SCB Bank&amp;rsquo;s lack of OpenBanking support means their clients are stuck with transaction statements in PDF format, courtesy of the SCB Easy App.</description></item><item><title>AWS CloudDay Thailand: Secure from Day-0: Increase Your Security Posture with Temporary Elevated Access and AWS IAM Identity Center</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-sso-elevator-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-sso-elevator-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading The recent AWS CloudDay Thailand at the Queen Sirikit National Convention Centre was an extraordinary convergence of tech aficionados. The sheer turnout—numbering in the thousands—made it clear: Security, efficiency, and cutting-edge technologies are at the forefront of every organization&amp;rsquo;s strategic plan.
Amid the vastness of the event, the Developer Lounge was a distinctive gem. Though smaller in scale, its value was undeniable, offering a blend of intimacy and innovation where in-depth discussions and exchanges thrived.</description></item><item><title>AWS User Group Meetup: AWS Spot Pricing with Terraform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading Set against the backdrop of the tech-forward AWS Office in Bangkok, the AWS User Group Meetup was a melting pot of innovation and collaboration. For CTOs and startup owners, understanding the pulse of the latest in cloud technology is crucial. This gathering provided a vibrant platform to explore, question, and share the most recent advancements in AWS.
My Own Perspective Link to heading One of the prime concerns for any CTO or startup owner is maximizing efficiency without inflating costs.</description></item><item><title>AWS Meetup – DevTalk in Bangkok: Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-vault-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-vault-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading At the recent AWS Meetup – DevTalk in Bangkok, I joined a group of cloud aficionados and professionals, representing a wide range of industries. Organized by the AWS User Group Thailand, this event underscored the importance of security in the AWS ecosystem—a critical concern for startups, seasoned businesses, and especially for leaders like CTOs and DevOps professionals.
The event was a resounding success, attracting a packed audience of 500 attendees who were eager to delve into the latest trends and insights in the world of AWS and cloud technologies.</description></item><item><title>LProbe: A Secure, Open-Source Local Health Check Solution</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/lprobe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/lprobe/</guid><description>LProbe: A One-Stop-Shop Tool for Secure, Local Health Checks Link to heading Even if your app is functioning, that doesn’t always mean it’s working correctly. For you to securely and easily ensure your local container is healthy before the system fails, FivexL developed an open-source automated local health check solution - LProbe.
A vivid example is an eternal timeout: your app doesn’t crash but keeps waiting for a system response.</description></item><item><title>Where no Windows Machine? Luck of space? Travel a lot? Let's use AWS as is Cloud Gaming platform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudgaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudgaming/</guid><description>Why Could Gaming? What is the Problem? Link to heading Usually, for PC gaming, it is required to have a nice and fresh PC. But time does not stand still; there are many things that change us. The simplest one is that our PCs just get old, and we can&amp;rsquo;t run new titles at high specs anymore, just because of hardware limitations.
What&amp;rsquo;s next? If we are going to update our setup, this means a huge upfront cost.</description></item><item><title>Book: The 6 Types of Working Genius, Patrick M. Lencioni (2022)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/the-6-types-of-working-genius/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/the-6-types-of-working-genius/</guid><description>https://www.amazon.com/Types-Working-Genius-Understand-Frustrations-ebook/dp/B09XGPCM36
The 6 Types of Genius Link to heading #1 The Genius of Wonder refers to the ability to think deeply and ask questions about the world around us. It involves speculation and curiosity, and the desire to seek answers and take action. Those who possess this genius tend to naturally engage in these activities and find it easy to become absorbed in observing and questioning their surroundings, considering whether things could be different or if there is untapped potential.</description></item><item><title>Book: Rework, Jason Fried, David Heinemeier Hansson (2010)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/rework/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/rework/</guid><description>https://www.amazon.com/Rework-Jason-Fried/dp/0307463745
Takedowns Link to heading In the beginning, it is said that it is difficult to draw up 5-year business plans in an environment of rapid change. I would go with the strategy of still creating an action plan, but calling it a yearly guess. About company size, the book reminds us, that being small is not too bad. Further in the book, we will talk about hiring, so here it’s more about the fact that an increase in the number of people does not always increase productivity in general.</description></item><item><title>Book: Terraform Up and Running 3.0, Yevgeniy Brikman (2022)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/terraform-up-and-running/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/terraform-up-and-running/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Book: Propaganda, Edward Bernays (2004)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/propaganda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/propaganda/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Book: Atomic Habits, James Clear (2018)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/atomic-habits/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</guid><description>Developers often hardcode credentials on a public or private GitHub repository, ramping up data leakage risks. It’s hardly better to store static credentials in the .aws/credentials folder on a server or a local operator machine. As american cryptographer, writer, and computer security specialist, Bruce Schneier, says: . &amp;ldquo;Only amateurs attackWe machines; professionals target people.&amp;rdquo; Therefore, you, not your hardware, is at risk.
By executing fraudulent software, cybercriminals can easily steal all the data from the folder or a whole directory with your, your friends’, and clients’ credentials.</description></item><item><title>What Is AWS CloudTrail, and Why Do You Need It</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</guid><description>Don’t have enough resources to set up a security department but want to stay on top of your AWS CloudTrail events? Find out how the CloudTrail-to-Slack Terraform module by FivexL solves this problem for startups and small teams.
Terraform Module for AWS CloudTrail — An Effective Security Tool Link to heading While large corporations have their own Security Operations Centers (SOCs) responsible for information security and can afford expensive solutions, startups usually don’t have enough resources and time to set up such a luxury.</description></item><item><title>How To Save Resources With the Terraform Module for AWS Spot Instances</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</guid><description>Saving money on Amazon Web Services (AWS) Spot Instances can be a challenging task. Keep in mind that it is essentially an auction. Although prices don’t fluctuate as rapidly as on exchanges, they can still increase until they reach the on-demand rate. Sometimes it lasts for a day or two, but other times — up to several months, which can double the cost.
How do you avoid a situation in which, for example, everything went perfect in November, but in December, the prices doubled amid the holiday hype — and you got not only an expensive system but also one with interruptions?</description></item><item><title>Book: Investing in your 20s and 30s, Eric Tyson (2017)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/investing-in-your-20s-and-30s/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/investing-in-your-20s-and-30s/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/migrate-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/migrate-to-hugo/</guid><description>I was happy to switch to Hugo I think this format looks much more modern</description></item><item><title>Book: A Song Of Ice and Fire, George R. R. Martin (2012)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/a-song-of-ice-and-fire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/a-song-of-ice-and-fire/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Film: Catch Me If You Can, Steven Spielberg (2002)</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/catch-me-if-you-can/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/catch-me-if-you-can/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/about/</guid><description>Long story short Hello there! I&amp;rsquo;m Vladimir Samoylov, a cloud engineering and DevOps aficionado. From engineer to CTO &amp;amp; Cloud Consultant, my journey is fueled by a passion for AI, automation, and continuous learning. Let&amp;rsquo;s connect and transform your tech vision into reality! The Beginning of an Unexpected Journey Link to heading &amp;ldquo;It all started quite unexpectedly. Picture this: I was the CTO at an EdTech company, navigating the complexities of technology, when I stumbled upon the world of DevOps.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/contact/</guid><description>Follow me, @cageyv.</description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/education/</guid><description>2010 - 2014: Moscow State University of Instrument Engineering and Computer Science Master Degree, GPA: 4.55 / 5 Computers, complexes, systems, and networks 2006 - 2010: Moscow College of Informatics and Computer Engineering Engineer’s degree, GPA: 4.23 / 5 Computer software and automated systems Additional Education Link to heading AWS Link to heading https://www.aws.training/
2021 aws certified solutions architect associate
2020 aws technical professional
2020 aws cloud economics
2020 aws business professional</description></item><item><title>Experience</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/experience/</guid><description>2020 - present: FivexL consulting team Skills: Amazon ECS · AWS Lambda · AWS Security · GitHub · Amazon Web Services (AWS) · Terraform Various projects Clients meet where they are and no matter how chaotic and confusing were, everything was managed to be put on the rails of predictability All wishes and requirements for the project were carefully listened to. Deep understanding of client requirements, needs, and challenges Skeletons in the closet are not a problem.</description></item><item><title>First snippet</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/first/</guid><description>This content is in snippets/first/index.md
pwd</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/projects/</guid><description>Secure, durable and scalable Infrastrature for Europenian Crypto Exchange Platform Link to heading “It was an essential approach for us to be able to scale moving forward.” and &amp;ldquo;first application deployed in just two weeks.” (c)
Migration from AWS EC2 to AWS ECS (Containers) like a hot swap wheel change on a moving race car Pipeline migration from Buddyworks to GitHub Actions Serverless solution (AWS ECS Fargate + AWS Lambda) Security part: Database are not available for all world any more, CMK KMS as general for encryption, AWS WAF + Cloudflare for incoming traffic protection Resource Optimization: Resource usage has been reduced by more than 50% and we will improve the ecology of the world.</description></item><item><title>Recommend</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/recommend/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/recommend/</guid><description>Servies Link to heading Numbeo Do you want to compare Cities or Countries? Cost of living and Quality of Life database is here. DuoLingo The free, fun, and effective way to learn a language! Onward Ticket Quickly book a Flight Reservation for your Visa Application. Verifiable on Airline&amp;rsquo;s Websites. SafetyWing Insurance for nomdas. Travel medical insurance. They cover people from all over the world, while outside their home country. italki It helps me.</description></item><item><title>Second snippet</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/second/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/snippets/second/</guid><description>This content is in snippets/second/index.md
ls -la</description></item></channel></rss>