<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>spot on Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/tags/spot/</link><description>Recent content in spot on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/tags/spot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS User Group Meetup: AWS Spot Pricing with Terraform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading Set against the backdrop of the tech-forward AWS Office in Bangkok, the AWS User Group Meetup was a melting pot of innovation and collaboration. For CTOs and startup owners, understanding the pulse of the latest in cloud technology is crucial. This gathering provided a vibrant platform to explore, question, and share the most recent advancements in AWS.
My Own Perspective Link to heading One of the prime concerns for any CTO or startup owner is maximizing efficiency without inflating costs.</description></item><item><title>How To Save Resources With the Terraform Module for AWS Spot Instances</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</guid><description>Saving money on Amazon Web Services (AWS) Spot Instances can be a challenging task. Keep in mind that it is essentially an auction. Although prices don’t fluctuate as rapidly as on exchanges, they can still increase until they reach the on-demand rate. Sometimes it lasts for a day or two, but other times — up to several months, which can double the cost.
How do you avoid a situation in which, for example, everything went perfect in November, but in December, the prices doubled amid the holiday hype — and you got not only an expensive system but also one with interruptions?</description></item></channel></rss>