<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opensource on Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/tags/opensource/</link><description>Recent content in Opensource on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/tags/opensource/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>scb-to-moneywiz: Import Bank Transactions from SCB Easy (Thailand) to MoneyWiz</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/scb-to-moneywiz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/scb-to-moneywiz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">
 Introduction:
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#introduction">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Navigating financial management can be a tricky affair, especially without cutting-edge banking technology. But for users of MoneyWiz, an ingenious script is making life easier. This tool specifically aids in importing SCB Bank transactions, transforming a tedious task into a smooth, automated process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-challenge-with-scb-bank">
 The Challenge with SCB Bank:
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#the-challenge-with-scb-bank">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we approach the end of 2023, SCB Bank&amp;rsquo;s lack of OpenBanking support means their clients are stuck with transaction statements in PDF format, courtesy of the SCB Easy App. Not exactly convenient for those who need to keep track of their finances regularly. This is where our script steps in, offering a practical solution for MoneyWiz users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LProbe: A Secure, Open-Source Local Health Check Solution</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/lprobe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/lprobe/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="lprobe-a-one-stop-shop-tool-for-secure-local-health-checks">
 LProbe: A One-Stop-Shop Tool for Secure, Local Health Checks
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#lprobe-a-one-stop-shop-tool-for-secure-local-health-checks">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Even if your app is functioning, that doesn’t always mean it’s working correctly. For you to securely and easily ensure your local container is healthy before the system fails, FivexL developed an open-source automated local health check solution - &lt;a href="https://github.com/fivexl/lprobe" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">LProbe&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
A vivid example is an eternal timeout: your app doesn’t crash but keeps waiting for a system response. If you receive no alert that there is no response within, let’s say, 30 seconds, you may not notice something is wrong. Here comes a health check to ensure your app is working correctly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>