<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SpeakUp on Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/series/speakup/</link><description>Recent content in SpeakUp on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/series/speakup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting started with Amazon Bedrock Studio</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</guid><description>AWS Sumit Bangkok 2024 Link to heading The event itself was huge. This year it was special one. AWS will launch Bankgon region in 2025. And this is a awesome news for all of us. Many companies are waiting for this moment. And I was happy to be a part of this event. Miss that one? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, you can catch up the next one in the next year.</description></item><item><title>AWS CloudDay Thailand: Secure from Day-0: Increase Your Security Posture with Temporary Elevated Access and AWS IAM Identity Center</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-sso-elevator-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-sso-elevator-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading The recent AWS CloudDay Thailand at the Queen Sirikit National Convention Centre was an extraordinary convergence of tech aficionados. The sheer turnout—numbering in the thousands—made it clear: Security, efficiency, and cutting-edge technologies are at the forefront of every organization&amp;rsquo;s strategic plan.
Amid the vastness of the event, the Developer Lounge was a distinctive gem. Though smaller in scale, its value was undeniable, offering a blend of intimacy and innovation where in-depth discussions and exchanges thrived.</description></item><item><title>AWS User Group Meetup: AWS Spot Pricing with Terraform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading Set against the backdrop of the tech-forward AWS Office in Bangkok, the AWS User Group Meetup was a melting pot of innovation and collaboration. For CTOs and startup owners, understanding the pulse of the latest in cloud technology is crucial. This gathering provided a vibrant platform to explore, question, and share the most recent advancements in AWS.
My Own Perspective Link to heading One of the prime concerns for any CTO or startup owner is maximizing efficiency without inflating costs.</description></item><item><title>AWS Meetup – DevTalk in Bangkok: Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-vault-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-vault-in-bkk/</guid><description>Event review Link to heading At the recent AWS Meetup – DevTalk in Bangkok, I joined a group of cloud aficionados and professionals, representing a wide range of industries. Organized by the AWS User Group Thailand, this event underscored the importance of security in the AWS ecosystem—a critical concern for startups, seasoned businesses, and especially for leaders like CTOs and DevOps professionals.
The event was a resounding success, attracting a packed audience of 500 attendees who were eager to delve into the latest trends and insights in the world of AWS and cloud technologies.</description></item></channel></rss>