<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aws on Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in aws on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Where no Windows Machine? Luck of space? Travel a lot? Let's use AWS as is Cloud Gaming platform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudgaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudgaming/</guid><description>Why Could Gaming? What is the Problem? Link to heading Usually, for PC gaming, it is required to have a nice and fresh PC. But time does not stand still; there are many things that change us. The simplest one is that our PCs just get old, and we can&amp;rsquo;t run new titles at high specs anymore, just because of hardware limitations.
What&amp;rsquo;s next? If we are going to update our setup, this means a huge upfront cost.</description></item><item><title>Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</guid><description>Developers often hardcode credentials on a public or private GitHub repository, ramping up data leakage risks. It’s hardly better to store static credentials in the .aws/credentials folder on a server or a local operator machine. As american cryptographer, writer, and computer security specialist, Bruce Schneier, says: . &amp;ldquo;Only amateurs attackWe machines; professionals target people.&amp;rdquo; Therefore, you, not your hardware, is at risk.
By executing fraudulent software, cybercriminals can easily steal all the data from the folder or a whole directory with your, your friends’, and clients’ credentials.</description></item><item><title>What Is AWS CloudTrail, and Why Do You Need It</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</guid><description>Don’t have enough resources to set up a security department but want to stay on top of your AWS CloudTrail events? Find out how the CloudTrail-to-Slack Terraform module by FivexL solves this problem for startups and small teams.
Terraform Module for AWS CloudTrail — An Effective Security Tool Link to heading While large corporations have their own Security Operations Centers (SOCs) responsible for information security and can afford expensive solutions, startups usually don’t have enough resources and time to set up such a luxury.</description></item><item><title>How To Save Resources With the Terraform Module for AWS Spot Instances</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</guid><description>Saving money on Amazon Web Services (AWS) Spot Instances can be a challenging task. Keep in mind that it is essentially an auction. Although prices don’t fluctuate as rapidly as on exchanges, they can still increase until they reach the on-demand rate. Sometimes it lasts for a day or two, but other times — up to several months, which can double the cost.
How do you avoid a situation in which, for example, everything went perfect in November, but in December, the prices doubled amid the holiday hype — and you got not only an expensive system but also one with interruptions?</description></item></channel></rss>