<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aws on Vladimir Samoylov</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in Aws on Vladimir Samoylov</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cageyv.dev/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why is RDS not just an Open-Source PostgreSQL? From Classic RDS to Aurora DSQL</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-amazon-aurora-dsql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-amazon-aurora-dsql/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aws-user-group-singapore">
 AWS User Group Singapore
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#aws-user-group-singapore">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was invited to the AWS User Group Singapore to talk about the PostgreSQL in AWS and about the Amazon Aurora DSQL. It was a great event. I was happy to meet many engineers and architects from the community. Usuage of the PostgreSQL in Singapore is quite huge, around half of audince was using it.
Organization of the event was perfect. I was happy to be a part of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MVP on AWS: PostgreSQL</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-mvp-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-mvp-postgresql/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-postgresql">
 Why PostgreSQL?
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#why-postgresql">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that you already decided on PostgreSQL as your database. Why? Because it is a powerful, open-source object-relational database system with over 30 years of active development, correct? We will leave the problem of where and how to store data for another time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="rds-aurora-postgresql-compatible-or-rds-postgresql">
 RDS Aurora (PostgreSQL Compatible) or RDS PostgreSQL
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#rds-aurora-postgresql-compatible-or-rds-postgresql">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If there are no specific requirements, we may select Aurora as the default option.
Storage systems are the key difference between the two. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about being out of space. Aurora will help you. Aurora will automatically scale the storage up to 128 TB (November 2024). &amp;ldquo;The data is automatically replicated across Availability Zones, your data is highly durable with less possibility of data loss.&amp;rdquo; You can have one instance with data in 3 different places. If you want to add another region, it will give us six different places in the world where data is stored. Magic, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with Amazon Bedrock Studio</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-bedrock-and-accounts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-bedrock-and-accounts/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="aws-sumit-bangkok-2024">
 AWS Sumit Bangkok 2024
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#aws-sumit-bangkok-2024">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The event itself was huge. This year it was special one. AWS will launch Bankgon region in 2025. And this is a awesome news for all of us. Many companies are waiting for this moment. And I was happy to be a part of this event. Miss that one? Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, you can catch up the next one in the next year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS RDS Data API and CloudTrail. Who drop the table?</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-rds-data-api/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-rds-data-api/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">
 Introduction
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#introduction">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Amazon Web Services (AWS) continually innovates to enhance user experience and efficiency. A prime example of this is the recent update to the RDS Data API, particularly for Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL-Compatible Edition. This update is a game-changer, as it offers users the ability to access Aurora clusters via a secure HTTP endpoint. The key here is the removal of rate limits and the elimination of the need for database drivers and managing connections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Multiverse of Hosting a Static HTML File on AWS</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-static-hosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-static-hosting/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, we dive into the versatile and dynamic world of AWS, exploring the numerous avenues for hosting a simple, yet pivotal, web element - the static HTML file. AWS, known for its robust and expansive cloud services, offers a plethora of methods for this seemingly straightforward task. Each method comes with its own set of features and benefits, suitable for various needs and complexities. From the efficient S3 buckets to the comprehensive AWS Amplify, we&amp;rsquo;re covering a spectrum of options that cater to different scales and requirements. So, let&amp;rsquo;s unpack these methods and see how they align with your DevOps strategies, business goals, and IT needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Navigating the Path to AWS Solutions Architect Professional Certification</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-solutions-architect-professional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-solutions-architect-professional/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cageyv.dev/images/aws-certified-solutions-architect-professional.webp" alt="badge">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="embarking-on-a-transformative-journey">
 Embarking on a Transformative Journey
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#embarking-on-a-transformative-journey">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Two years ago, I set out on an educational expedition with AWS, starting with the AWS Solutions Architect Associate certification. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m elated to share my achievement of the AWS Solutions Architect Professional certification. This accomplishment marks a significant milestone in my professional journey.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="empowered-by-the-aws-community-builders-program">
 Empowered by the AWS Community Builders Program
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#empowered-by-the-aws-community-builders-program">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My path was significantly bolstered by the support of the AWS Community Builders program. Their generous provision of a complimentary exam coupon not only alleviated financial constraints but also fueled my motivation to succeed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS CloudDay Thailand: Secure from Day-0: Increase Your Security Posture with Temporary Elevated Access and AWS IAM Identity Center</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-sso-elevator-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-sso-elevator-in-bkk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="event-review">
 Event review
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#event-review">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The recent AWS CloudDay Thailand at the Queen Sirikit National Convention Centre was an extraordinary convergence of tech aficionados. The sheer turnout—numbering in the thousands—made it clear: Security, efficiency, and cutting-edge technologies are at the forefront of every organization&amp;rsquo;s strategic plan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amid the vastness of the event, the Developer Lounge was a distinctive gem. Though smaller in scale, its value was undeniable, offering a blend of intimacy and innovation where in-depth discussions and exchanges thrived.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS User Group Meetup: AWS Spot Pricing with Terraform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-ec2-spot-in-bkk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="event-review">
 Event review
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#event-review">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Set against the backdrop of the tech-forward AWS Office in Bangkok, the AWS User Group Meetup was a melting pot of innovation and collaboration. For CTOs and startup owners, understanding the pulse of the latest in cloud technology is crucial. This gathering provided a vibrant platform to explore, question, and share the most recent advancements in AWS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://cageyv.dev/images/posts/speakup_aws_ec2_spot_in_bkk/1.webp" alt="FistImage">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-own-perspective">
 My Own Perspective
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#my-own-perspective">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the prime concerns for any CTO or startup owner is maximizing efficiency without inflating costs. During the meetup, I delved into AWS Spot Pricing through Terraform, showcasing how organizations can achieve both. The Terraform Module for AWS Spot Instances isn&amp;rsquo;t just a tool; it&amp;rsquo;s a strategy. By automating Spot Max Prices management, it prevents potential budget overruns and unnecessary resource consumption – every DevOps professional&amp;rsquo;s dream.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS Meetup – DevTalk in Bangkok: Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-vault-in-bkk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/speakup-aws-vault-in-bkk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="event-review">
 Event review
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#event-review">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the recent AWS Meetup – DevTalk in Bangkok, I joined a group of cloud aficionados and professionals, representing a wide range of industries. Organized by the AWS User Group Thailand, this event underscored the importance of security in the AWS ecosystem—a critical concern for startups, seasoned businesses, and especially for leaders like CTOs and DevOps professionals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The event was a resounding success, attracting a packed audience of 500 attendees who were eager to delve into the latest trends and insights in the world of AWS and cloud technologies. The event featured a series of talks by industry experts, including Werner Vogels, Donnie Prakoso, Vit Niennattrakul, Ankit Mehta, and myself. The event was a testament to the growing interest in cloud technologies and the need for a community-driven approach to knowledge-sharing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where no Windows Machine? Luck of space? Travel a lot? Let's use AWS as is Cloud Gaming platform</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudgaming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudgaming/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="why-could-gaming-what-is-the-problem">
 Why Could Gaming? What is the Problem?
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#why-could-gaming-what-is-the-problem">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Usually, for PC gaming, it is required to have a nice and fresh PC. But time does not stand still; there are many things that change us. The simplest one is that our PCs just get old, and we can&amp;rsquo;t run new titles at high specs anymore, just because of hardware limitations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s next? If we are going to update our setup, this means a huge upfront cost. We have to pay right now or make a commitment to pay (such as credit) for a high-end PC. And you know what? After a while, it will get old too. I went through that cycle years ago, when I played a lot more than I do today. Every 2-3 years, I just needed to buy a new PC. At the same time, it is bad for the environment, because we just can&amp;rsquo;t make proper hardware utilization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Basics in AWS or How To Get Rid of Hardcoded Credential and Reduce Data Leakage Risks with aws-vault</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-vault/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developers often hardcode credentials on a public or private GitHub repository, ramping up data leakage risks. It’s hardly better to store static credentials in the .aws/credentials folder on a server or a local operator machine. As american cryptographer, writer, and computer security specialist, Bruce Schneier, says: . &amp;ldquo;Only amateurs attackWe machines; professionals target people.&amp;rdquo; Therefore, you, not your hardware, is at risk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By executing fraudulent software, cybercriminals can easily steal all the data from the folder or a whole directory with your, your friends’, and clients’ credentials. Even the AWS support team is exhausted with constant tickets regarding stolen credentials from public Git repos. Here&amp;rsquo;s why if you commit keys, expect an email in 3-5 minutes saying that the IAM policy has been applied. It means that you can’t get rid of the policy or destroy exposed credentials.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is AWS CloudTrail, and Why Do You Need It</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-cloudtrail-to-slack/</guid><description>&lt;p>Don’t have enough resources to set up a security department but want to stay on top of your AWS CloudTrail events? Find out how the CloudTrail-to-Slack Terraform module by &lt;a href="https://fivexl.io/" class="external-link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">FivexL&lt;/a> solves this problem for startups and small teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="terraform-module-for-aws-cloudtrail--an-effective-security-tool">
 Terraform Module for AWS CloudTrail — An Effective Security Tool
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#terraform-module-for-aws-cloudtrail--an-effective-security-tool">
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading">&lt;/i>
 &lt;span class="sr-only">Link to heading&lt;/span>
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>While large corporations have their own Security Operations Centers (SOCs) responsible for information security and can afford expensive solutions, startups usually don’t have enough resources and time to set up such a luxury. Therefore, they have to look for simple security solutions to protect their data. Understanding the pain of limited resources, FivexL developed the Cloudtrail-to-Slack Terraform Module.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To Save Resources With the Terraform Module for AWS Spot Instances</title><link>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cageyv.dev/posts/aws-ec2-spot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Saving money on Amazon Web Services (AWS) Spot Instances can be a challenging task. Keep in mind that it is essentially an auction. Although prices don’t fluctuate as rapidly as on exchanges, they can still increase until they reach the on-demand rate. Sometimes it lasts for a day or two, but other times — up to several months, which can double the cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do you avoid a situation in which, for example, everything went perfect in November, but in December, the prices doubled amid the holiday hype — and you got not only an expensive system but also one with interruptions? Let&amp;rsquo;s examine why this happens. For this, let&amp;rsquo;s look at Spot Instance allocation strategies and see how you can use the Terraform module with no issues and save money at the same time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>